Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Southern Conference records 1946-2001 IBT0024
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Southern Conference Records
1946-2001
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
IBT0024
0.5 Linear Feet
This collection contains meeting minutes, legal documents, agreements, and reports. The material dates from 1946-2001. These are the records of the Southern Conference of Teamsters, a regional governance body in the structure of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters.
Arrangement
Organized into 1 series: Records
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains meeting minutes, legal documents, agreements, and reports. The material dates from 1946-2001. These are the records of the Southern Conference of Teamsters, a regional governance body in the structure of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters.
Biographical / Historical
Within the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, between 1937 and 1995, members of the union met and exchanged ideas on a regional basis. These regional organizations were called Area Conferences. In the U.S. there were four area Area Conferences: the Western Conference of Teamsters formed in 1937, the Southern Conference of Teamsters formed in 1944, the Central States Conference of teamster formed in 1953, and the Eastern Conference of Teamsters also formed in 1953. Canadian Teamsters had their own Canadian Conference of Teamsters, known today as Teamsters Canada. Area Conferences met annually to discuss general issues facing the IBT and to hold discussion more directly relevant to IBT Trade Divisions: contract negotiations, organizing campaigns, workplace disputes, etc. For example, when the Central States Conference met, after the general sessions, delegates would meet based on the trades they represented: the brewery and soft drink delegates coming together, cannery delegates coming together, dairy delegates coming together, etc. In this way, the IBT was strengthened in terms of both national and regional coordination of efforts. The Area Conferences came under criticism during the General Presidency of Ron Carey. Making the argument that they were redundant and wasteful, Carey disbanded them in 1995.
Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions; Conferences; Labor
- Records, 1946-2001; Series 1; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the records of the Southern Conference of Teamsters from 1946-2001 and includes proceedings of the sixth through tenth, and thirteenth annual meetings of the southern conference, as well as motor frieght agreements.
  - Proceedings Of The 6th Annual Meeting, 18-21 March 1946; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings Of The 7th Annual Meeting, 14-18 April 1947; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Proceedings Of The 8th Annual Meeting, 1-4 March 1948; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Proceedings Of The 9th Annual Meeting, 20-22 April 1949; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Proceedings Of The 10th Annual Meeting, 4-8 May 1950; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Proceedings Of The 13th Annual Meeting, 5 May 1954; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proceedings Of The 13th Annual Meeting - Building and Construction Trade Division Meeting, 7 May 1954; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Southern Region Meeting, 27 February - 1 March 2000; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Southern Region Meeting, 4-8 March 2001; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Over The Road Motor Freight Agreements, 1958-1964; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)